<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hi, I am Yusuf Avcı on Yusuf Avcı</title>
    <link>https://yusufavci.dev/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hi, I am Yusuf Avcı on Yusuf Avcı</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 02:12:53 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yusufavci.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Creating a Docker Image and Uploading it to DockerHub</title>
      <link>https://yusufavci.dev/techblog/docker-hub/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 00:48:05 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yusufavci.dev/techblog/docker-hub/</guid>
      <description>I created a nginx web-server container winth docker by using a simple dockerfile.
FROM nginx EXPOSE 80 COPY _site/ /usr/share/nginx/html Then, create an image via:
docker build . -t imagename:imagetag Optional: Running The Image docker run [--name containername] [-p outport:inport] imagename:imagetag Pushing The Image First, tag the image. Registry host is optional if you are using DockerHub. username/repositoryname suffices.
docker tag [OPTIONS] IMAGE[:TAG] [REGISTRYHOST/][USERNAME/]NAME[:TAG] Login to your docker registry. Again, server is optinal for dockerhub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Learning</title>
      <link>https://yusufavci.dev/blog/on-learning-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 17:05:53 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yusufavci.dev/blog/on-learning-1/</guid>
      <description>I love learning things. I could spend my whole life reading and researching stuff and I probably wouldn’t get bored. But that’s not how things get done. You sometimes have to take action and do something with the things you know. That is, there is a trade-off between learning more to make things better and having the actual time to do things. Mongtaigne states in his Essays that the youth (until around 20) is the time to learn and the rest of your life is time to do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WSO2 APIM Beginner&#39;s Guide</title>
      <link>https://yusufavci.dev/techblog/wso2-apim-beginner-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 00:48:05 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yusufavci.dev/techblog/wso2-apim-beginner-1/</guid>
      <description>Starting to use WSO2 was a hellish experince in the beginning. There are numerous products. The documentation expects you to have some understanding of the system and most of the tutorial’s are that way too. There is also an Enterprise Integrator and Integration Studio that comes with it. Note that I’m new in WSO2 and this post may contain some misinformation. If you want to contribute, you can mail yusufavci99 at gmail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Basics</title>
      <link>https://yusufavci.dev/techblog/docker-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 00:48:05 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yusufavci.dev/techblog/docker-start/</guid>
      <description>Docker is a containerization tool used to create images to run across different computers. It&amp;rsquo;s different from a VM because the containers share the same OS. For docker to run, Docker Desktop should be running in the background and WSL2 should be activated (Windows 10). In Windows, a process named vmmem runs in the background with WSL2 and it uses some RAM. This app is the VM in which the containers run.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Map Sizes In Games</title>
      <link>https://yusufavci.dev/blog/on-game-maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2021 17:05:53 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yusufavci.dev/blog/on-game-maps/</guid>
      <description>I’ve always thought that bigger maps are better in games because there are is a bigger world to explore. However, I recently realized that sometimes bigger games didn’t feel big. For example, Just Cause 3 has a gigantic map of 2000km2. However, it doesn’t feel as large as, say GTA SA. Then I realized that mere size is not enough to create a sense of a bigger world. What the games need is variety.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bullet Zone</title>
      <link>https://yusufavci.dev/projects/bulletzone/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 18:11:14 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yusufavci.dev/projects/bulletzone/</guid>
      <description>APK File
A bullet hell style casual mobile game created in Unity. The game is 3D and the projectiles come both horizontally and vertically. Yellow points show the points where the player can go. Each dodged projectile increases your score. The game was done in 3 hours. I am planning to update the game and put it on the Play Store.
APK File</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yusuf &amp; Semiha Special Burger</title>
      <link>https://yusufavci.dev/yemek/yusuf-semiha-burger/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 00:48:05 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yusufavci.dev/yemek/yusuf-semiha-burger/</guid>
      <description>Malzemeler
200-250 gr. iri çekim yağlı kıyma. Çedar. Olası soslar ketçap mayonez hardal acı sos sriracha vs. Hamburger ekmeği Soğan tercihe göre karamelize Sıvı yağ (az) Baharat olarak tuz toz biber karabiber şart sarımsak tozu vs. eklenebilir. İsteğe Bağlı Malzemeler
Domates Mantar turşu Salam Marul Patates Etin döküm bir tavada mühürlenip her iki tarafını iyice pişirmek gerekiyor. Sonrası birleştirme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Çemen (Artun)</title>
      <link>https://yusufavci.dev/yemek/cemen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 00:48:05 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yusufavci.dev/yemek/cemen/</guid>
      <description>Malzemeler
Zeytinyağı Salça (Biber &amp;amp; Domates) Sarımsak Ceviz (Olsa süper olur) Ezine veya Süzme peynir Karabiber Salçayı zeytinyağında kavurduktan sonra sarımsağı da kavur. İçine son olarak ceviz peynir ve karabiber ekle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kabak Yoğurtlama</title>
      <link>https://yusufavci.dev/yemek/kabak-yogurtlama/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 00:48:05 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yusufavci.dev/yemek/kabak-yogurtlama/</guid>
      <description>Malzemeler
Kabak Yoğurt (Az), Süzme Yoğurt (Çok) Sarımsak Ceviz Kabağı az zeytinyağı veya yağsız ölene kadar ocakta kendi suyunda pişir.
Parçalanmış sarımsak yoğurt ve cevizle birleştir.
Not: Tarifin orijinalinde sadece süzme yoğurt vardı ama ben az miktarda yoğurtla kıvamı hafif açmayı tercih ettim.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CRSG Author Module</title>
      <link>https://yusufavci.dev/projects/crsgauthormodule/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 17:17:08 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yusufavci.dev/projects/crsgauthormodule/</guid>
      <description>Code Review Serious Game Author Module was my summer 2020 internship project. I created a serious game used in teaching the code review process. Players should fix the reviewed codes. Players&amp;rsquo; submissions are evaluated and scored.
Used JS, Ace Editor Library, Judge0 API, Ajax, Firebase.
There are 3 levels to select. The serious game looks like this. Resizing is possible. Here you can see the reviews, see hints. Players can see the solutions if they want to give up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Augcards</title>
      <link>https://yusufavci.dev/projects/augcards/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 17:15:09 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yusufavci.dev/projects/augcards/</guid>
      <description>This is our Senior project. It is a mobile AR card game creation tool. You can find many details and images in the reports.
Game creators can create their games with custom rules by using our event system. There are dozens if images and explanations and source code in the links I am providing.
Detailed Info
Final Report</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Hugo</title>
      <link>https://yusufavci.dev/techblog/hugolearning1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 00:48:05 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yusufavci.dev/techblog/hugolearning1/</guid>
      <description>Essential Commands // To start a project hugo new site first_site // To run server -D to show drafts hugo server -D // To create a post dirname optional hugo new dirname/post_name.md Add a theme to config.toml
theme = &amp;#34;theme-name&amp;#34; Content Organization // Create this to make /dir1/dir2 // accessible hugo new dir1/dir2/_index.md Archetypes You can change the archetypes to change the front matter defaults. Like dir1.md. If directroy exists, it will be used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebGL 3D Animation</title>
      <link>https://yusufavci.dev/projects/webglanimationdemo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 17:18:43 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yusufavci.dev/projects/webglanimationdemo/</guid>
      <description>Source Code
I and Sonat Uzun created 3D keyframe animations with WebGL. It is possible to save/load keyframes to create different animations with this program. We created the model using primitives and hierarchy. I&amp;rsquo;ve created the model using triangle vertices and hierarchy. I didn&amp;rsquo;t use any modeling program.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unity Gyroscope Demo</title>
      <link>https://yusufavci.dev/projects/unityrollgyrodemo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 17:18:16 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yusufavci.dev/projects/unityrollgyrodemo/</guid>
      <description>Source Code
Created a basic roll-a-ball game with Unity. It uses gyroscope sensors of the phone to controll the ball. There are spikes and a hole that can kill you.
Falling in a hole can kill you. When the player dies, they see a death message. When the player wins, they see a congratulations message. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Combining Game</title>
      <link>https://yusufavci.dev/projects/combininggame/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 17:16:49 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yusufavci.dev/projects/combininggame/</guid>
      <description>Source Code
This is a Doodle God like game made with Java. You can combine elements to create new elements in the game. It also features a game editor in which you can create your game content such as new elements and recipes.
Players can see available elements.
Player can selectt an element by clicking on it.
By selecting a second element, players can attempt combining them. If the combinati is sucessful, a new element can be unlocked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebGL Ray Tracer</title>
      <link>https://yusufavci.dev/projects/webglraytracer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 17:16:23 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yusufavci.dev/projects/webglraytracer/</guid>
      <description>Source Code
Sonat Uzun and I created an interative, procedurally generated ray tracer with WebGL. It can display triangles, spheres and cubes.
It has numerous options. Randomized trace order randomizes pixel rendering order. This results in blurry images instead of slow scans. Use texture creates the spheres with a checkers pattern texture. Moving spheres makes the spheres move in a random direction. Add options create a random sized/colored shape in a random location on screen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turkish Checkers</title>
      <link>https://yusufavci.dev/projects/turkishcheckers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 17:16:04 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yusufavci.dev/projects/turkishcheckers/</guid>
      <description>Source Code
I created a Turkish Checkers game with AI. It uses the minimax algorithm. It can beat novice players without much trouble.
The game starts in this position. The playable moves are highlighted when you click on a piece. A Mid-Game image. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Favorite Animes</title>
      <link>https://yusufavci.dev/blog/favoriteanime/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 17:05:53 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yusufavci.dev/blog/favoriteanime/</guid>
      <description>I listed my favorite animes. They are all great
Serial Experiments Lain
SEL is a mind bending experience that I don&amp;rsquo;t want to spoil. It starts like a generic horror/crime anime but It&amp;rsquo;s far from it. You must watch it if you&amp;rsquo;re a computer geek.
Cowboy Bebop
It has a perfect setting and atmosphere. I very much like the world they created in Cowboy Bebop. It&amp;rsquo;s weakness is it&amp;rsquo;s low continuity in my opinion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Favorite Movies</title>
      <link>https://yusufavci.dev/blog/favoritemovies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 17:05:45 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yusufavci.dev/blog/favoritemovies/</guid>
      <description>All of these movies have a special place for me. My descriptions will be very short because I don&amp;rsquo;t want to spoil much.
Barry Lyndon This movie is beautiful. I cannot comprehend how this movie was filmed in 1975. And the story was incredibly believeable.
Kill Bill Top notch action. And if you&amp;rsquo;re not watching this because you&amp;rsquo;re afraid that it&amp;rsquo;s too gross or violent, just watch it.
Pulp Fiction I&amp;rsquo;m not sure why I like this movie that much.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Favorite Games</title>
      <link>https://yusufavci.dev/blog/favoritegames/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 17:04:25 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yusufavci.dev/blog/favoritegames/</guid>
      <description>I love playing games and here are some of my favorite games. I&amp;rsquo;m a metroidvania fan so there might too many metroidvania games in this list. The order of games are totally random.
Terraria This game is not a simple Minecraft clone. It has the most diverse original content in a game I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen. Weapons are never the copy of the older ones. You can always find something new in the game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CityBuilder</title>
      <link>https://yusufavci.dev/projects/citybuilder/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 18:23:20 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yusufavci.dev/projects/citybuilder/</guid>
      <description>I am working on a mobile city builder game. I implemented panning, zooming and house building. I am planning to add various residentials, commercials etc. to make it a rich strategy game. I will update here when I complete the game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Catan</title>
      <link>https://yusufavci.dev/projects/catan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 17:14:54 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yusufavci.dev/projects/catan/</guid>
      <description>Made a computer adaptation of Catan game as a group of five for Object-Oriented Software Engineering class. Worked with Sockets and Threads. Mainly worked on the networking part. More Info</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tsu</title>
      <link>https://yusufavci.dev/projects/tsu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 17:16:34 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yusufavci.dev/projects/tsu/</guid>
      <description>Made an Android application for travel guidance as a group of six. The program has trivia about countries, a flexible dictionary, world clocks. Gained experience in deployment and improving Android cross-device compatibility.
Detailed Info</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
