<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Yusuf Avcı</title>
    <link>https://yusufavci99.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Yusuf Avcı</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 16:58:43 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yusufavci99.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>On Learning</title>
      <link>https://yusufavci99.github.io/blog/on-learning-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 17:05:53 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yusufavci99.github.io/blog/on-learning-1/</guid>
      <description>I love learning things. I could spend my whole life reading and researching stuff and I probably wouldn’t get bored. But that’s not how things get done. You sometimes have to take action and do something with the things you know. That is, there is a trade-off between learning more to make things better and having the actual time to do things. Mongtaigne states in his Essays that the youth (until around 20) is the time to learn and the rest of your life is time to do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Map Sizes In Games</title>
      <link>https://yusufavci99.github.io/blog/on-game-maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2021 17:05:53 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yusufavci99.github.io/blog/on-game-maps/</guid>
      <description>I’ve always thought that bigger maps are better in games because there are is a bigger world to explore. However, I recently realized that sometimes bigger games didn’t feel big. For example, Just Cause 3 has a gigantic map of 2000km2. However, it doesn’t feel as large as, say GTA SA. Then I realized that mere size is not enough to create a sense of a bigger world. What the games need is variety.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Favorite Animes</title>
      <link>https://yusufavci99.github.io/blog/favoriteanime/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 17:05:53 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yusufavci99.github.io/blog/favoriteanime/</guid>
      <description>I listed my favorite animes. They are all great
Serial Experiments Lain
SEL is a mind bending experience that I don&amp;rsquo;t want to spoil. It starts like a generic horror/crime anime but It&amp;rsquo;s far from it. You must watch it if you&amp;rsquo;re a computer geek.
Cowboy Bebop
It has a perfect setting and atmosphere. I very much like the world they created in Cowboy Bebop. It&amp;rsquo;s weakness is it&amp;rsquo;s low continuity in my opinion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Favorite Movies</title>
      <link>https://yusufavci99.github.io/blog/favoritemovies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 17:05:45 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yusufavci99.github.io/blog/favoritemovies/</guid>
      <description>All of these movies have a special place for me. My descriptions will be very short because I don&amp;rsquo;t want to spoil much.
Barry Lyndon This movie is beautiful. I cannot comprehend how this movie was filmed in 1975. And the story was incredibly believeable.
Kill Bill Top notch action. And if you&amp;rsquo;re not watching this because you&amp;rsquo;re afraid that it&amp;rsquo;s too gross or violent, just watch it.
Pulp Fiction I&amp;rsquo;m not sure why I like this movie that much.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Favorite Games</title>
      <link>https://yusufavci99.github.io/blog/favoritegames/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 17:04:25 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yusufavci99.github.io/blog/favoritegames/</guid>
      <description>I love playing games and here are some of my favorite games. I&amp;rsquo;m a metroidvania fan so there might too many metroidvania games in this list. The order of games are totally random.
Terraria This game is not a simple Minecraft clone. It has the most diverse original content in a game I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen. Weapons are never the copy of the older ones. You can always find something new in the game.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
